dayofhappiness.net 2019-05-08

# Action for Happiness

**We take your privacy very seriously and we ask that you  read this privacy notice carefully. It contains important information about who we are, how and why we collect, store, use and share your information and your rights in relation to this.**

**Who we are and what we do**

Action for Happiness is a [Registered Charity](http://beta.charitycommission.gov.uk/charity-details/?regid=1175160&subid=0) providing a range of services to help people take action for a happier and more caring world. Everything we do is in support of our mission and we have no commercial or political aims.

When you interact with Action for Happiness, you may choose to share some personal information with us, such as your name and contact details. Action for Happiness acts as the Data Controller for the data you provide and this Privacy Policy outlines when and how we use any information that you give us, in line with the General Data Protection Regulations 2018.

We are committed to ensuring that your privacy is protected. When you provide us with information, it will only be used in accordance with this Policy. Action for Happiness may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. This updated Policy is effective as of 17 May 2018 and gives you more control over your information and more clearly explains how we use it.

**How This Policy Applies**

This Policy describes the information we collect from you, how we use that information and our legal basis for doing so. It also covers whether and how that information may be shared and your rights and choices regarding the information you provide to us. By choosing to share your personal data with us and using the services offered by Action for Happiness, you're acknowledging you have understood and agreed to the terms this Privacy Policy.

**When and how we collect your data**

We do not collect any personal information about you except when you specifically and knowingly provide such information. You may choose to share your data with us in various ways, including:

  * By signing up to join our movement
  * By booking to attend one of our events or courses
  * By supporting one of our online campaigns
  * By registering your interest to hear about opportunities to get involved with our work (e.g. to discover courses near you or find out how to be a course leader)
  * By ordering our resources (e.g. our postcards or school Toolkits)
  * By interacting with us in other ways where you choose to share your data

When you provide your personal data in this way you are giving us permission to hold this data and process your information in appropriate ways, in line with this Privacy Policy.

You may provide this information to us via various online platforms which we use to fulfil our charitable objectives, including our website and a small number of trusted and secure third-party services we use for managing event bookings and capturing data via online forms and surveys.

Your data will be held and processed in a limited number of carefully controlled systems, which we also use to fulfil our charitable objectives, including the trusted third-party platforms we use for email communications, relationships management and secure data storage and backup.

We only collect information for legitimate purposes in ways which are adequate, relevant and limited to what is necessary in support of our charitable aims. We endeavour to ensure that the information we hold is accurate and, where necessary, kept up to date. And we take steps to ensure that any personal data that is inaccurate is rectified or erased without delay.

If you wish to access, update or request deletion of your personal information we will ensure that such requests are always acted on in a timely and appropriate way (see details below).

**What do we do with the data you provide**

We use the information you share with us to provide you with useful and relevant information in support of our mission. This includes:

  * Sending you relevant information about the specific part of our work that you have engaged with (e.g. a course you are attending or the resources you have ordered)
  * Sending you occasional updates about our work which we feel are relevant and appropriate
  * Letting you know about upcoming events, courses or activities near you, where these are considered to be relevant and appropriate

Our processing of your data is based on one or both of the following two legal bases:

  * **Consent** : where possible we will ask for your consent to use your data. Your consent is given to us when you choose to share your information with us in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * **Legitimate Interest** : in some cases, we may process your data to pursue our legitimate interests in a way that might reasonably be expected as part of running our charity and that does not materially impact your rights, freedom or interests.

We have procedures in place to ensure that information you provide is processed lawfully, fairly and in a transparent way. We will only hold your information on our systems for the period necessary to fulfil the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy or until you request it is deleted.

**Opting out from our communications**

You can opt out from our communications at any time. This can be done by clicking on the "Unsubscribe" link at the bottom of our emails or by replying to any of our communications and asking to opt out from receiving these updates.

**Accessing your data and keeping it up to date**

If you would like to find out what information we hold about you, or let us know about any changes to your information, you can do this at any time by writing to us at [info@actionforhappiness.org](mailto:info@actionforhappiness.org)

[](mailto:info@actionforhappiness.org)When sending you an email we will also often include a link where you can see the data you have provided to us and make changes to this if needed to keep it up to date.

**How we keep your data secure**

We take your privacy very seriously and we are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. To prevent unauthorised access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect.  This includes protection against unauthorised or unlawful processing and against accidental loss, destruction or damage.

**When and how we may share your data**

In order to carry out our charitable aims, your data may be processed by one or more trusted service providers which we use to operate elements of our service and process data on our behalf. For example, if you order printed materials from us, we may need to share your address with a shipping company, so they can deliver these resources to you.

Where such data is provided to third parties it will always be on a limited and controlled basis and they will not have permission to contact you for any other purposes.

The information you provide to us will not be shared with any other entity or organisation without your explicit consent.

**Links to other websites and resources**

Our website contains links to other websites and resources of interest. Once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over these other websites. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this Privacy Policy. You should exercise caution and look at the Privacy Policy applicable to the website in question.

**Asking for your personal data to be deleted**

As described above, you are able to opt out of receiving our general updates emails or invitations to courses and events at any time by clicking "Unsubscribe" or by writing to us.

You may also ask at any time for your personal data to be deleted from all Action for Happiness systems, by writing to us at [info@actionforhappiness.org](mailto:info@actionforhappiness.org)

If you withdraw your consent to us processing your data, we will delete your personal data from all systems on which we hold it within two weeks.

**Data Protection Officer**

To contact our Data Protection Officer, please email [info@actionforhappiness.org](mailto:info@actionforhappiness.org) Or you can contact us in writing via post at:

Action for Happiness, WeWork, 3 Waterhouse Square, 138 Holborn, London EC1N 2SW.

**Complaints or queries**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or any of the procedures set out in it, please contact **Mark Williamson** at [info@actionforhappiness.org](mailto:info@actionforhappiness.org).

We take your privacy very seriously and aim to respond quickly and flexibly to any queries or complaints that are raised.

You also have the right to raise concerns with Information Commissioner's Office on 0303 123 1113 or at <https://ico.org.uk/concerns>
